Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
Center for Digital Research in the Humanities University of Nebraska–Lincoln
- Records of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia; Law, Appellate, and Criminal Records; Case Papers 1802-1863
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, Negro Arnold (a slave belonging to Mrs. Elzey); 1820, June; for assault and battery (Box 192, Folder 31)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, John Warden; 1820, June; for "forging... free papers for slaves, and selling them as such" (Box 192, Folder 35)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. George Davis; 1820, June; $100.00 "in case Negro Samuel your slave shall not be of good behaviour for the space of six months from this date [February 6, 1820]" C. Tippitt "Maintenance of Negro Phillip injail from March the 6 to April the 8 boath days included" $16.89. (Box 192, Folder recognizances)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Henrietta Elzey; 1820, June; $100.00 Arnold’s assault on Edward Kerr, "& the said negro Arnold shall also keep the peace generally... til the next Court... ." (Box 192, Folder recognizances)
  - Appeal Bonds, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Presentments, Rough Bundle, Statement of William Thornton, magistrate; 1820, June; that John Waters, constable, beat him for issuing a warrant against Mrs. Waters for stealing a chicken from "the coloured woman Henny Gray" (Box 192, Folder recognizances)
  - Imparlances, 1-598, 1820, June (Box 193)
  - Imparlances, 604-1045, Judicials, 1-55, 1820, June (Box 194)
  - Judicials, 58-167, James Young v. John Addison; 1820, June; includes an appraisal (no values listed) of "1 Negro Man named Dennis, 1 Brown horse, 1 Bay ditto" (Box 195, Folder 71)
  - Judicials, 169-283, 1820, June (Box 196)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. George Nebison; 1820, December; "free negro," for stealing soap and candles worth $10 (Box 197, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. George Copley; 1820, December; "free negro," for stealing soap and candles worth $10 (Box 197, Folder 8)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Theophilus Rounds; 1820, December; "ree mulatto," for stealing 39 cedar posts worth $18 (Box 197, Folder 19)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Negress Julia; 1820, December; "free negress," for stealing "one delf bowl" worth 12 cents (Box 197, Folder 20)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Peggy Reynolds; 1820, December; "free negress," for stealing one hog worth $3 (Box 197, Folder 30)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. William Davis; 1820, December; "free negro," for stealing a saddle and bridle worth $100 (Box 197, Folder 43)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. John Miller; 1820, December; for stealing "one negro slave named John Hall" belonging to Susannah Smith, worth $200 (Box 197, Folder 45)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. John Miller; 1820, December; "for kidnapping and afterwards offering to sell Daniel Brown a free negro" (Box 197, Folder 46)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Kitty Jenkins; 1820, December; "free negress," for stealing 2 shifts ($4), 1 petticoat ($3), 1 cambric frock ($3), 2 handkerchiefs ($1) and 2 aprons ($1.50), total: $12.50 (Box 197, Folder 49)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. John Allen; 1820, December; "free mulatto," for stealing a pair of boots worth $7; [There is no docket book for the December term of 1820 (the last year in which the court sat during June and December); the April 1821 docket book lists Criminal Appearances numbers and punishments: 46, George Nebeson, "5 stripes"; 47, George Copely, ﬁve; 45, "Negro Julia," ﬁve; 51 and 79, John Allen, $5 ﬁne and 25 stripes on each] (Box 197, Folder 51)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, 1820, December; Habeas corpus petition of Basil Lee, a free man being held "as a Run away Slave" in the Washington County jail (Box 197, Folder rough bundle)
  - Criminal Trials, Rough Bundle, 1820, December; Bench warrants for George Copley and George Nebeson, each described as "a coloured man," charged with stealing soap and candles worth $10.00 (see Criminal Trials 7 and 8, above) (Box 197, Folder rough bundle)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 1-189, 1821 (Box 198, Folder 80)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 191-283, Lawson Clark v. Zadock Wilson; 1821,; replevin of a "negro man named Cato [Valued at $375] aged about thirty three years the slave of the said Lawson Clark which the said Zadock Wilson hath taken and unjustly detained against sureties and pledges..." (Box 199)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 285-496, 1821 (Box 200)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 503-1059, 1821 (Box 201)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 1072-1301, Richard Davis v. John Stiles; 1821,; "one dark mulatto boy named Harry about 15 years" [Value illegible] and "one negro boy named Garrison about 13 years old" [$300] (Box 202, Folder 1148)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 1072-1301, Humphrey Belt v. Jonathan T. Bush; 1821,; replevin of "one Negro woman Delia" [$250]; "one Negro girl Maria" [$150]; "one Negro Boy Ambrose" [$150]; "one Negro girl Charlotte" [$80] (Box 202, Folder 1201)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 1072-1301, Humphrey Belt v. Jonathan T. Bush; 1821,; replevin of "one Negro man Ceasar" [$350]; "one child named Mary" [$20]; two horses [$70] (Box 202, Folder 1202)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 1305-1623, William D. Merrick v. Thomas B. Pottinger; 1821,; hire of Rose Matthews’ "Negro man Frederick" for $80 a year (Box 203, Folder 1354)
  - April, Civil Trials, 4-270, Jack Garretson et al. v. Janet Lingan; 1821,; petitions for freedom of Jack Garretson, Richard Luckett, Richard Johnson and Rachel Garretson (Box 204, Folder 185)
  - April, Civil Trials, 273-434, 1821 (Box 205)
  - April, Civil Trials, 439-547, John P. Van Ness v. Theresa Baltimore; 1821,; "a free black woman" rental agreement (Box 206, Folder 484)
  - April, Civil Trials, 439-547, Rezin Wooden v. James Smith; 1821,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says Rezin Wootton (Box 206)
  - April, Civil Trials, 550-617, 1821 (Box 207)
  - April, Civil Trials, 619-698, 1821 (Box 208)
  - April, Civil Trials, 700-782, Ormond F. Butler V. Damuel Winsatt; 1821,; "To maintenance of Negro Horatio for safe keeping in jail" 120 days @ 50 cents $60.00 partially paid with 4 cords oak wood 27.50 (Box 209, Folder 768)
  - April, Civil Trials, 784-865, 1821 (Box 210)
  - April, Civil Trials, 867-941, Esaias Travers v. Jonathan Appler; 1821,; "a black boy" delivering bread for a baker used tally sticks to keep track of the customers’ bills (Box 211, Folder 920)
  - April, Civil Trials, 942-1012, 1821 (Box 212)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1014-1092, 1821 (Box 213)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1094-1187, 1821 (Box 214)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1190-1255, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. John Allen; 1821,; "a freeman of colour" (stole a coat worth $10) (Box 215, Folder 79)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1190-1255, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. John Allen; 1821,; (stole two watches worth $15; 1 set earrings worth $5) (Box 215, Folder 80)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1190-1255, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. Rachel Glasco; 1821,; (evidently white, "or dealing with slaves, for receiving stolen goods" worth $7) (Box 215, Folder 81)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1190-1255, Criminal Appearances, U.S. v. William Johnson alias Harvey Hanson; 1821,; "a free black man" (stole a coat worth $30) (Box 215, Folder 85)
  - April, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Negro Thomas Miles; 1821,; (arson; burned house of John Gardiner) (Box 216, Folder 14)
  - April, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1821; Habeas corpus of "James Hart, a mulatto... is a free man born of a white woman; it is ordered that he be discharged from his imprisonment" (Box 216, Folder rough bundle)
  - April, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1821; Habeas corpus of "George Landrick a Negro boy about 16 years" (evidently his father had bound him in apprenticeship as a waiter, but his master had "sublet" him for more money than he was paying George’s father, who wanted to break the contract) (Box 216, Folder rough bundle)
  - April, Criminal Trials, Appeal Bonds, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, U.S. v. Henrietta Elzey & Benjamin Harrison; 1821,; "Arnold (the slave man of Mrs H Elzey) to keep the peace with all good citizens ofthis county..." (Box 216, Folder 13)
  - April, Imparlances, 10-304, 1821 (Box 217)
  - April, Imparlances, 315-821, 1821 (Box 218)
  - April, Judicials, 2-123, Robert & John Oliver v. Thomas Ewell; 1821,; (debt of $1220 + interest, total $1590.78) "Levied as per schedule the Negroes levied on sold at private sale by Defendant to Plaintiff" & taken by Plaintiff" to Baltimore" list includes "one negro woman Clarah" $350; "girl Moria" (12 years old) $200; "boy Louis" (8) $200; "girl Sophia" (5) $150; "girl Eliza" (4) $125 Total $1025 (Box 219, Folder 24)
  - April, Judicials, 126-228, Robert S. Beckley v. Washington Boyd; 1821,; "Mulatto Andrew who has between 4 & 5 years to serve" valued at $200 sold to David Minor for $130 towards settlement of a debt; "negro John Giles a slave for life" not sold (Box 220, Folder 131)
  - April, Judicials, 230-360, Joseph King, Jr., v. William H. Barron; 1821,; "l negro boy Tom," Value $250, sold for $100; "1 negro girl Jane," Valued at $200, sold for $250; "Barbara," valued at $200, sold for $130 (Box 221, Folder 273)
  - April, Judicials, 230-360, Union Bank of Georgetown v. Alban Clarke; 1821,; appraised at $500 "1 negro man (Mulatto) Francis" (Box 221, Folder 305)
  - April, Judicials, 230-360, H. Marshall V. D. Renner & D. Bussard Renner; 1821,; gave the DC. Marshal "full liberty to take my negro Boys Mosse aged about 26 year & Negro Gilbert aged 24 year at any time he may wish, to satisfy the one half of a judgment against Renner & Bussard..." Bussard similarly agreed to give up his slaves Nate and Lucindy (Box 221, Folder 403)
  - April, Judicials, 364-466, 1821 (Box 222)
  - April, Judicials, 469-588, 1821 (Box 223)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 2-175, John D. Freeman v. Adam Mayn; 1821,; "Neagro Man by the name of Adam Vincent" hired for one year: $80 plus clothing (Box 224, Folder 93)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 2-175, Francis Sewall v. Adam Mayne; 1821,; "Neagro man by the Name of Jack Vincent" hired at the same rate (Box 224, Folder 94)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 2-175, Hezekiah Hall v. Charles W. Butler; 1821,; replein of "one negro girl named Mary and an infant child about four months old" (Box 224, Folder 123)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 176-289, Richard Johnson v. Janet Lingan; 1821,; petition for freedom (Box 225, Folder 263)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 176-289, Richard Luckett v. Janet Lingan; 1821,; petition for freedom (Box 225, Folder 264)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 291-459, 1821 (Box 226)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 463-733, 1821 (Box 227)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 737-927, 1821 (Box 228)
  - October, Civil Trials, 2-273, Michael Keogh v. Edgar McCarty; 1821,; "l Negro Girl" $200.00 "account current" (Box 229, Folder 19)
  - October, Civil Trials, 2-273, William Henry v. Gustavus Beall; 1821,; involves the fraudulent sale of two "negro girls," 2 unnamed, by a third party (Box 229, Folder 125)
  - October, Civil Trials, 275-433, Elizabeth Purdy v. Joseph Ratcliff; 1821,; personal estate of Mary Yates includes 5 m., 3 f., ages 2-38, assessed Value $2750 (Box 230, Folder 275)
  - October, Civil Trials, 440-555, 1821 (Box 231)
  - October, Civil Trials, 557-649, 1821 (Box 232)
  - October, Civil Trials, 651-762, 1821 (Box 233)
  - October, Civil Trials, 765-878, 1821 (Box 234)
  - October, Civil Trials, 881-998, Leonard Dunbar v. James Ball Dunbar; 1821,; "a boy of colour aged about twenty one years," claimed that he was illegally sold—that is, within a year of his former master’s moving to Washington from Virginia (Box 235, Folder 994)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. John C. Harper; 1821,; "for dealing with slaves...Housing Stolen Goods" (Box 236, Folder 17)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Jacob Robinson; 1821,; "a free Negroe" stole clothing worth $1.50 (Box 236, Folder 49)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Thomas Brown; 1821,; alias John Sims, "a free Negroe" stole clothing worth $2.00 (Box 236, Folder 53)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Thomas Brown; 1821,; alias John Sims stole clothing worth $200 (Box 236, Folder 54)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Cornelius Davis; 1821,; "a free Negroe labourer" assault & battery on a constable (Box 236, Folder 56)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Henry Chub; 1821,; "a free Negroe labourer" assault & battery (Box 236, Folder 67)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Henry Johnson; 1821,; "a free Negroe labourer" stole a "pocket book" worth $1.00 (Box 236, Folder 68)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Clinton Adams; 1821,; "a free Negroe labourer" stole food worth $1.00 (Box 236, Folder 69)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Thomas Brown; 1821,; "a colourd man,..labourer" stole cloth (?) Worth 50 cents (Box 236, Folder 70)
  - October, Imparlances, 1821 (Box 237)
  - October, Judicials, 1-123, Linthicum & Magruder v. Green; 1821,; "one negro girl named Mary about thirteen and fourten years old" $200.00 (Box 238, Folder 2)
  - October, Judicials, 1-123, Riggs & Gaither v. Barron; 1821,; "two negro men called Sam and Jack" $300.00 "Boy called by the name of Henry about 20 years old" $400.00 (Box 238, Folder 24)
  - October, Judicials, 1-123, Ann E. Peyton v. Richard G. Edwards; 1821,; "l Negro Girl named Ellen about 9 years old" $140.00 (Box 238, Folder 43)
  - October, Judicials, 124-225, 1821 (Box 239)
  - October, Judicials, 226-335, 1821 (Box 240)
  - October, Judicials, 336-467, 1821 (Box 241)
  - October, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1821; Habeas corpus of Nicholas Cole, "a free man of colour who hath been committed as a Runaway Slave...is now held illegally in conﬁnement in the prison of Washiington County. He is prepared to prove his freedom..." (Box 242, Folder rough bundle)
  - October, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1821; Warrant for "a Black man who calls his name Henry Lucas taken up as a runaway..." (Box 242, Folder rough bundle)
  - October, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1821; Warrant for "John Perkins...a runaway negro...(who states that he is free)...." (Box 242, Folder rough bundle)
  - October, Recognizances, Rough Bundle, 1821; Warrant for "Landon Parks...a runaway negro slave..." (Box 242, Folder rough bundle)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 1-129, Negro Isaac v. Bennet Jarboe; 1822,; petition for freedom (Box 243, Folder 24)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 131-250, 1822 (Box 244)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 252-467, William Hillbush v. Rebecca B. Stannard; 1822,; "one negro girl Henrietta and her child William" $300.00 (Box 245, Folder 381)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 252-467, Negro Daniel v. —— Ballard; 1822,; petition for freedom; includes a document by Francis Scott Key; looks like a complicated case (Box 245, Folder 390)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 252-467, Edward Semmes v. Enos Schell; 1822,; "one negro girl named Matilda" attached for debt (Box 245, Folder 426)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 469-743, 1822 (Box 246)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 748-993, 1822 (Box 247)
  - April, Civil Trials, 9-202, 1822 (Box 248)
  - April, Civil Trials, 205-365, 1822 (Box 249)
  - April, Civil Trials, 367-508, 1822 (Box 250)
  - April, Civil Trials, 564-634, Negro Chloe & children v. William Marbury; 1822,; petition for freedom (Box 251, Folder 594)
  - April, Civil Trials, 641-740, 1822 (Box 252)
  - April, Civil Trials, 742-837, A. Waring v. D. Kirby & D. Reintzel; 1822,; "Hire of Negro Boy Robert" 14 months at $35 a year and clothing (2 shirts) = $42.33 (Box 253, Folder 775)
  - April, Civil Trials, 742-837, Mary Ann Magruder v. Robert Brown; 1822,; "I Negro Boy named Alfred" $200 "I Negro Girl Kitty" $400 attached by marshal (Box 253, Folder 785)
  - April, Civil Trials, 840-931, 1822 (Box 254)
  - April, Civil Trials, 932-1036, 1822 (Box 255)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1039-1162, 1822 (Box 256)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1169-1244, 1822 (Box 257)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1246-1322, 1822 (Box 258)
  - April, Civil Trials, 1325-1432, 1822 (Box 259)
  - April, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, U.S. v. Negroe John Glasgow; 1822,; stole "one barrel of hogs bristles" worth $5 (Box 260, Folder 59)
  - April, Imparlances, Recognizances, Rough bundle, 1822; Recognizance of "Negro Susan Johnson," a witness in the case of Peter Belt, a sick black man killed by some folk remedies administered by his wife and "Nancy Swann a Coloured Woman"—Susan Johnson was a witness in the case (Box 261)
  - April, Imparlances, Recognizances, Rough bundle, 1822; Recognizance of James Tench "for himself and two Negro Petitioners...for the safe delivery of negro Emily and Mary" (ﬁled March 1822) (Box 261)
  - April, Judicials, 1-114, 1822 (Box 262)
  - April, Judicials, 115-225, Richard Gill v. James Watson; 1822,; attachment of "l negro man named William," valued at $300, and $600 worth of "household & kitchen furniture" (Box 263, Folder 204)
  - April, Judicials, 227-341, 1822 (Box 264)
  - April, Judicials, 378-540, H. Goldsborough v. I. Mudd, C. Glover & G. Miller; 1822,; in a list of property attached is "l negro girl" valued at $300 (Box 265, Folder 519)
  - April, Judicials, 378-540, John Wheelwright v. Joseph Gales, Jr.; 1822,; in a list of property attached is "one Negro Girl named Susan" valued at $250 (Box 265, Folder 539)
  - April, Titlings for Writs, Titlings for Executions, 1822 (Box 266)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 3-132, Benjamin Berry v. William Holt; 1822,; "one negro boy James" $350.00 (Box 267, Folder 43)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 3-132, Negro Leanna & Child v. John Pumphrey; 1822,; petition for freedom (Box 267, Folder 77)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 133-229, 1822 (Box 268)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 231-329, 1822 (Box 269)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 344-520, Hercules Daurey v. Cartwright Tippett; 1822,; "Negro Maria Dorsey and child" $250.00 (Box 270, Folder 351)
  - October, Civil Appearances, 344-520, Negro Charlotte v. Tobias Watkins; 1822,; petition for freedom (Box 270, Folder 481)
  - October, Civil Trials, 8-297, 1822 (Box 271)
  - October, Civil Trials, 301-590, R.M. Scott v. B. Wood & B.M. Robertson; 1822,; "one negro man named Ben" $50.00 [sic] (Box 272, Folder 338)
  - October, Civil Trials, 301-590, James Hepburn v. Thomas Crown; 1822,; "Thomas Crown hired Mr. Hepburn’s man Tom at $24 per month" $91.00 (Box 272, Folder 548)
  - October, Civil Trials, 592-702, 1822 (Box 273)
  - October, Civil Trials, 706-848, 1822 (Box 274)
  - October, Civil Trials, 850-966, Robert Henley v. Samuel Miller; 1822,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says Henly (Box 275, Folder 959)
  - October, Appeals, Criminal Appearances, Criminal Trials, Noah Stinchcomb v. Jmes Shields; 1822,; "hire of my negroe man Orange" $17/month (Box 276, Folder 49)
  - October, Imparlances, Recognizances, Negro Isaac v. Alexander Talbott; 1822,; petition for freedom (Box 277, Folder 182)
  - October, Judicials, 1-157, O.M. Linthicum & N. Magruder v. R. Wells; 1822,; "one boy Thomas about 14 years" $250.00 (Box 278, Folder 21)
  - October, Judicials, 159-331, 1822 (Box 279)
  - October, Judicials, 343-544, Rough Bundle, Patriotic Bank of Washington v. Thomas G. Addison; 1822,; "Harry about 20 years" $400.00 "Daniel about 19 years" $400.00 (Box 280, Folder 347)
  - October, Judicials, 343-544, Rough Bundle, W.A. Bradley V. H. Ashton; 1822,; "l Negro Girl named Sally 16 years of age" $350.00 (Box 280, Folder 544)
  - October, Judicials, 343-544, Rough Bundle, 1822; Habeas Corpus Nat Tucker, "a black man," who claimed to have been kept two years in the county jail; James Burr, "a man of color" from New York, also held in the jail; and George Snow, "a white man...now confined in the Jail of the County of Washington at the instance of one Nancy Thomas a black girl who has sworn [him] to be the Father of a child begotten upon her body..." (Box 280, Folder rough bundle)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Negro Charlotte v. Lloyd Pumphrey; 1823,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says John Pumphrey (Box 281, Folder 10)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Nace Humphreys, Jr. v. William Berry; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 281, Folder 11)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Wood Humphreys v. William Berry; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 281, Folder 12)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Aquilla K. Arnold v. Phoeba Fenwick; 1823,; "one negro Man called Joseph" $250.00 (Box 281, Folder 25)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Nace Humphreys v. John B. Lambert; 1823,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says defendant is John Boswell (Box 281, Folder 27)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Nace Humphreys v. John Boswell; 1823,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says defendant is Henry Roberts (Box 281, Folder 50)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Negro Milly v. Basil Warring; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 281, Folder 56)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Susan Smith v. Thomas Johns; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 281, Folder 117)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Richard Johnson v. Janet Lingan; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 281, Folder 153)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 3-164, Richard Lucket v. Janet Lingan; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 281, Folder 154)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 165-279, 1823 (Box 282)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 281-480, David Randall v. John B. Reid; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 283, Folder 301)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 281-480, Vincent Gardner v. Thompson Simpson; 1823,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says Garner (Box 283, Folder 318)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 281-480, Negro Patty v. Charles Ratclilfe; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 283, Folder 330)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 281-480, Beall & Berry v. Goldsborough; 1823,; "one Negro Girl called Diana" $225.00 (Box 283, Folder 456, 458)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 483-833, William Jordan v. Lemuel Sawyer; 1823,; petition for freedom (Box 284, Folder 548)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 483-833, Negro Milley v. Thomas Massey; 1823,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Milly" (Box 284, Folder 582)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 483-833, Esther Humphreys v. John B. Lambert; 1823,; petition for freedom; Black Washingtonians says "Easther" (Box 284, Folder 623)
  - April, Civil Appearances, 835-1093, 1823 (Box 285)
  - April, Civil Trials, 3-307, 1823 (Box 286)
  - April, Civil Trials, 309-566, Richard Jones v. William Henry; 1823,; "One negro boy named Edward about 1 1 or 12 years of age" $300.00 (Box 287, Folder 493)
  - April, Civil Trials, 570-702, Nathan Moore v. Charles A. Pye; 1823,; for "apprehending" and "maintenance of Negro William in Jail" for 17 days $10.12 (Box 288, Folder 637)
  - April, Civil Trials, 570-702, Charles W. Boteler v. Hezekiah Hall; 1823,; "Will be sold on Tuesday June 21st 1821 at the central Market house (Site of the National Archives building) at 7 o clock a m the following Property to wit Negro Girl by the name of Mary with a small child about 5 months old..." (Box 288, Folder 647)